Spas Zdravkov Spasov

Sofia, Bulgaria

00359 (0)888 989 764

spas.z.spasov@gmail.com

github.com/metalevel-tech

askubuntu.com/users/566421



Year of birth 1980, single

Resume

Computers and computer science in general have been my hobby since I was eight years old. Last year I decided to follow my dreams and turn this hobby into a new professional career. I left my previous job, shortly after I applied to a JavaScript advanced course. I decided it is a good starting point, because of the possibility to work at frontend and backend in a single language, and because of my previous experience.

I'm having interest in DevOps area too. In my free time I like to read books, hiking, or gym. What I am looking for is the opportunity to focus my efforts to the right direction, to learn new things, and the challenges to solve tasks that are beyond my current knowledge.

Education

2010 – 2015 Doctor of Engineering Science in Automated Systems for Data Processing and Management Technical University of Sofia, Faculty of Mechanical Engineering, Department of Automation of Discrete Production Engineering.

2005 - 2007Master of Science in Computer Technologies in Mechanical Engineering Technical University of Sofia, Faculty of Machine Technology, Department of Technology of Machine Building and Metal Cutting Machines.

2001 – 2005 **Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering** Technical University of Sofia, Faculty of Machine Technology, Department of Technology of Machine Building and Metal Cutting Machines.

2000 - 2001Army service in Special Forces of Bulgarian Army, Paratrooper.

1995 – 1999 **Specialist Degree** High School of Machine Technologies, Pazardjik, Bulgaria, Department of Machine-Building and Device-Building.

Languages

**** Native Bulgarian

★★★☆ Conversational English

★☆☆☆☆ Basic Russian

Employment History

2019 – 2021 Management consultant at "Information Technologies and the Future of the Economic

Sofia, Bulgaria Science Foundation".

Positions and activities: Development of training programs and presentations of the company; Executive of trainings of the personal of the company; Consultant of ERP/PLM systems and industrial enterprise management; Project management; System administrator of the IT infrastructure of the company and support its Internet presence.

2017 – 2019 Management consultant at "Engineering Culture in the Management of the Future

Sofia, Bulgaria Foundation".

Positions and activities: Consultant of ERP/PLM systems and industrial enterprise management; Development of presentations of the company, acquiring new investors; Project management; System administrator of the IT infrastructure of the company.

2011 – 2017 Management consultant at "Trivium AD".

Yambol, Bulgaria Positions and activities: Consultant of ERP/PLM systems and industrial enterprise management; Project management; Development of training programs and executive of trainings of the personal of the customers.

2007 – 2011 Production engineer and technologist, at "Hydraulic Elements and Systems AD".

Yambol, Bulgaria Positions and activities: Production engineer, team leader, project manager, chief technologist of the metal-cutting processes with CNC machines.

2006 – 2007 Technologist at "Teximp S.A. branch Bulgaria".

Sofia, Bulgaria Positions and activities: Technologist, technical consultant, warehouse manager; service team coordinator.

2004 – 2006 Associate in the Laboratory of Mechanical Engineering Technology, at "Technical University *Sofia, Bulgaria* of Sofia".



Programming Languages, Services and Related IT Experence

★★★☆ Good experience, need more practice with SCSS and similar preprocessors. HTML/CSS ** * * * * * * * Few courses accomplished, experience with Functional and Object orientated paradigm. JavaScript Node.js ★★☆☆ Extensively used within the accomplished JS courses, continue to study it. React.js ★★★☆ Accomplished an Advanced JS with React course, continue to study it. TypeScript ★☆☆☆☆ Basic knowledge: This is the next goal after finishing the Node and React courses. PHP ★★☆☆☆ Basic knowledge: Creating relatively simple plugins for MediaWiki and WordPress. Lua ★★☆☆☆ Basic knowledge: Creating modules for MediaWiki. Python ★☆☆☆ Basic knowledge: Solving some hobby tasks. ★☆☆☆ Basic knowledge: Managing databases and users for CMS as MediaWiki and WordPress. MySQL Bash/Dash ★★★☆ Good experience with various tasks, both at Linux server and desktop environment. Linux Server ★★★☆ Deployment, administration and security of few production and dev servers (VPS). ★★★☆ Administration; HTTPS, HTTP/2, PHP/FPM, Mod Security, Mod Rewrite, Mod Proxy, etc. Apache2 WordPress ★★★☆☆ Deployment and setup, custom plugins created with HTML/CSS, JavaScript, PHP. MediaWiki ★★★☆ Deployment, and full setup, templates, extensions – HTML/CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Lua, etc. ApacheGuac ★★★☆☆ Used for few years as private RDP/VNC web client. ProxmoxVE ★★★☆ Used for few years as bare metal hypervisor at my dev lab. LXD/LXC ★★★☆☆ Experience with local and remote instances, containers deployment, setup, and backup. Docker ★★★☆☆ Basic usage; using and creating images and containers. Git ★★★☆☆ Basic CLI usage; Experience with GitHub, currently I'm learning about GitHub actions. Design/UI ★★☆☆ Experience with GIMP; Adobe Illustrator and PhotoShop. Experience with CAD/CAM. Microsoft365 ★★☆☆☆ Experience with Microsoft 365 (and Azure) basic setup and administration. PowerShell ★☆☆☆ Basic usage and scripting, in this count some basic experience with CMD batch scripting. Desktop ★★★★ Wide experience with Windows10 with WSL2, Kali Linux, Ubuntu and PopOS. **Browsers** ★★★★ Chromium and Firefox at Linux and Windows, DuckDuckGo at Android, Lynx at CLI. **Editors** 🛊 🛊 🛊 🏠 🔆 Visual Studio Code, Notepad++, Microsoft Office, OpenOffice, OnlyOffice, Nano, Vim.

Spas Zdravkov Spasov

Sofia, Bulgaria

00359 (0)888 989 764

spas.z.spasov@gmail.com

github.com/metalevel-tech

askubuntu.com/users/566421



Year of birth 1980

Resume

Computers and computer science in general have been my hobby since I was eight years old when I wrote my first program in Basic. Last year I decided to follow my dreams and turn this hobby into a new professional career. I left my previous job, shortly after I applied to a JavaScript advanced course with React. I decided JavaScript is a good starting point, because of the possibility to work at frontend and backend in a single language, and because of my previous experience. Meanwhile I've accomplished a few other JavaScript courses and two of the Cisco's NDG modules to examine my knowledge in Linux server's administration.

What I am looking for is the opportunity to learn new things and the challenges to solve tasks that are beyond my current knowledge. I'm a good student and fast learner, and I believe the most effective way to learn something is to teach it – that's why I was very valuable in my previous area.

I'm a Mechanical Engineer and Doctor of Engineering Science. My doctor's thesis is in the field of effective production plant management by the help of the modern systems for enterprise's knowledge management, so called ERP/PLM systems and related to them satellite software.

My employment history looks quite long – actually, it is not. For the past 10 years (2011 – 2021) I've worked as consultant and organizational engineer in three different companies, but they all belong to the same structure. One interesting fact during this period is that in 2018, as result of two developed by me documents, our team held a consultation meeting with the President of the Republic of Bulgaria.

Previously in (2007 – 2011), I was working as CNC machine technologist, production, and organizational engineer and later as project manager at a metal cutting company where the CEO was a board member of directors of the above organization. During the time of 2008 – 2010, our team managed to increase the efficiency of more than 60 production cells by 5 to 10 times via organizational changes and internal training using minimal investment. This was one of the key factors that allowed the company to survive during the crisis.

After defending my dissertation in 2015, I started supporting my employer's online presentation as a hobby. This was the beginning and the end of my previous career because I found out I enjoy working in this direction.

Since then, I've learned how to administer and automate Linux servers at a satisfactory level. I've gained semiprofessional experience with CMS systems as MediaWiki and WordPress - deployment, administration, and customization by creating features (plugins/extensions) in HTML/CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Lua, etc. Few years ago, I've setup a home laboratory, based on a bare metal hypervisor which allows me to learn many things about virtualization's technologies at a practical level. And here we come to the beginning of this resume.